American Eugenics Society Records 1916-1973 Mss.575.06.Am3
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence and Records (Box 1-20)
  - American Genetic Association (Box 13)
  - American Legislators Association (Box 13)
  - American Mercury, The (Box 13)
  - American Philosophical Society -- See AES - Archives (Box 13)
  - American Reporting Service (Box 13)
  - American Woman's Association (Box 13)
  - Ames, Blanche (Box 13)
  - Amherst High School (Box 13)
    Shutesbury - Leverett Survey
  - Anderson, D. F. (Box 13)
  - Anderson, J. V. (Box 13)
  - Anderson, Loyd L. (Box 13)
  - Anderson, Robert Van Vleck (Box 13)
  - Anderson, Teddy A. (Box 13)
  - Anderson, W. S. (Box 13)
  - Andrews, C. O. (Box 13)
  - Andrews, George Reid (Box 13)
  - Applebaum, S. J. (Box 13)
  - Armstrong, Lillian C. (Box 13)
  - Arndt, H., 1927 (Box 13)
    Presbyterian sermon on eugenics.
  - Arnold College (Box 13)
  - Art Metal Construction Company (Box 13)
  - Ascham, J. B. (Box 13)
  - Ashcraft, Alva (Box 13)
  - Ashley, Morgan (Box 13)
  - Ashton, Irene (Box 13)
  - Atlantic Refining Company (Box 13)
  - Auchincloss, Hugh D. (Box 13)
  - Bahr, Max (Box 13)
  - Baines, M. Carroll (Box 13)
  - Bajema, Carl Jay, 1965-1967; 3 folders (58 items) (Box 13)
    Correspondence in re Population Council Fellowship
    Biographical and personal data; Committee activities; Conferences and symposia; Educational matters -- Research programs; Fellowships, assistantships -- University of Michigan; Graduate study; Human genetics; Research support
  - Baker, Benjamin W. (Box 13)
  - Baker, Horace Forbes (Box 13)
  - Baker, Rufus C., 1926 (Box 13)
    Methodist sermon on eugenics.
  - Barker, Lewellys F. (Box 13)
  - Baron Picture Frame Works (Box 13)
  - Barrows, William Morton (Box 13)
  - Bawden, Frances T. (Box 13)
  - Beatty, T. B. (Box 13)
  - Bell, Whitfield J., Jr. -- See AES - Archives (Box 13)
  - Benedict, George, 1926 (Box 13)
    Jewish sermon on eugenics.
  - Bennett, G. E. (Box 13)
  - Bigelow, Frederick (Box 13)
  - Bishop, Edwin (Box 13)
  - Blackman, William F. (Box 13)
  - Bonner, Clarence A. (Box 13)
  - Bono, N. R. (Box 13)
  - Booth-Ferris Foundation (Box 13)
  - Brawner, Mary Elizabeth (Box 13)
  - Brigham, Carl C. (Box 13)
  - Bright, Mrs. Stanley (Box 13)
  - Bristol County (Mass.) Agricultural School (Box 13)
  - Brockton (Mass.) Agricultural Society (Box 13)
  - Brooker, Charles F. (Box 13)
  - Brown, J. A. (Box 13)
  - Brown, Orville Harry (Box 13)
  - Brown, Tracy (Box 13)
  - Brown, William H. (Box 13)
  - Brunn, Charles A. (Box 13)
  - Brush Foundation (Box 13)
  - Bryan, William A. (Box 13)
  - Bumstead, Dale (Box 13)
  - Burdick, C. Lalor (Box 13)
  - Burns, Vincent G. (Box 13)
  - Burr, Charles W. (Box 13)
  - Butler, Amos W. (Box 13)
  - Butler, W. F., 1926 (Box 13)
  - Byrd, P. W. (Box 13)
  - Cameron, Duncan P., 1926 (Box 13)
  - Cance, Alexander E. (Box 13)
  - Cannon, Walter Bradford (Box 13)
  - Carlson, Walter M., 1926 (Box 13)
    Congregational sermon on eugenics.
  - Carpenter, D. F. (Box 13)
  - Carter, L. V. (Box 13)
  - Castetler, E. F. (Box 13)
  - Cazort, Lee (Box 13)
  - Cazort, Sidney G. (Box 13)
    Cazort, Lee
    Chambers, Erle
  - Chamberlin, R. W. (Box 13)
  - Chambers, Erle (Box 13)
  - Champlain Valley Exposition, Inc. (Box 13)
  - Chase, Allan (Box 13)
  - Chester, Webster (Box 13)
  - Clark, Franklin S. (Box 14)
  - Clark, Walter E. (Box 14)
  - Close, Kenneth R., 1928 (Box 14)
  - Cockerell, T. D. A. (Box 14)
  - Cole, E. J. (Box 14)
  - Cole, L. J. (Box 14)
  - Colley, Thomas E., 1926 (Box 14)
  - Collins, H. H. (Box 14)
  - Conklin, Edwin G. (Box 14)
  - Connolly, Charles Parker, 1926 (Box 14)
    Church of the Christian Union sermon on eugenics.
  - Cook, Jason (Box 14)
  - Cook, O. F. (Box 14)
  - Copeland, Manton (Box 14)
  - Corwin, R. W. (Box 14)
  - Cotton, Henry A. (Box 14)
  - Coulter, Stanley (Box 14)
  - Courtright, Dudley V. (Box 14)
  - Crampton, Henry E. (Box 14)
  - Crane, Arthur G. (Box 14)
  - Crane, Harry W. (Box 14)
  - Cross, Shirley R. (Box 14)
  - Crossland, H. A. (Box 14)
  - Cummings, Byron (Box 14)
  - Cunningham, A. F., 1926 (Box 14)
    Lecture: "Eugenics, or, The Young Man Foursquare," delivered at high school in Burnet, Texas, for AES sermon contest.
  - Cutler, Ira A. (Box 14)
  - Dahlgren, Ulric (Box 14)
  - Danbury Agricultural Society (Box 14)
  - Davenport, Charles B. (Box 14)
  - Davis, Donald W. (Box 14)
  - Davis, Percy Allen, 1926 (Box 14)
    Christian Church sermon on eugenics.
  - Dexter, Roderick B. (Box 14)
  - Dixon, Roland B. (Box 14)
  - Dobson, T. (Box 14)
  - Doll, Edgar A. (Box 14)
  - Doloff, Charles H. (Box 14)
  - Donaldson, George Huntington, 1927 (Box 14)
  - Dowd, Jerome (Box 14)
  - Dowd, Quincy Lamartine, 1926 (Box 14)
    Congregational/Methodist (Federated) sermon on eugenics.
  - Down, E. E. (Box 14)
  - Doyle, S. R. (Box 14)
  - Duncan, Charles (Box 14)
  - Dunn, Frederick (Box 14)
  - Dunn, Matthew A. (Box 14)
  - East, Edward M. (Box 14)
  - Eastern States Exposition (Box 14)
  - Edmonds, T. J. (Box 14)
  - Elliot, E. A. (Box 14)
  - Elliott, Alfred O., 1926 (Box 14)
  - Elmer, Manuel (Box 14)
  - Elrod, M. J. (Box 14)
  - Emerick, Edson J. (Box 14)
  - Emlen, Samuel (Box 14)
  - Erickson (Box 14)
  - Essex Agricultural Society (Box 14)
  - Estabrook, Arthur H. (Box 14)
    Ladas, Constantine P.
  - Eugenics Committee of the U.S.A. (Box 14)
  - Eugenics Society, The (England) (Box 14)
  - Evans, Wayne (Box 14)
  - Fairchild, Henry P. (Box 14)
  - Fasten, Nathan (Box 14)
  - Fetter, Frank A. (Box 14)
  - Fetter, George C., 1926 (Box 14)
    Baptist sermon on eugenics.
  - Feuerlicht, Morris M. (Box 14)
  - Field, James A. (Box 14)
  - Fink, Bruce, in re (Box 14)
  - Fischoff, Ephraim (Box 14)
  - Fish, John E. (Box 14)
  - Fisher, Irving (Box 14)
    Osborn, Henry Fairfield
  - Flanders, Louis W. (Box 14)
  - Fleming and Reavely, Inc. (Box 14)
  - Flint, K. R. B. (Box 14)
  - Fordyce, O. O. (Box 14)
  - Fosdick, Harry E. (Box 14)
  - Fowler, Walter (Box 14)
  - Frandsen, Peter (Box 14)
  - Franklin County Fair Association (Box 14)
  - Fraser, C. McLean (Box 14)
    Macklin, C. C.
  - Fraser, Clara (Box 14)
  - Frazier, Charles K. (Box 14)
  - Freud Mugford Chambers Co., Inc. (Box 14)
  - Fryer, James R. (Box 14)
  - Funkhouser, W. D. (Box 14)
    Johnson, Roswell H.
  - Galton Publishing Company (Box 14)
  - Gammage, Grady (Box 14)
  - Gardner, H. B. (Box 14)
  - Gates, William H. (Box 14)
  - Gauthier, Carrie A. (Box 14)
  - Geiser, S. N. (Box 14)
  - Gemmill, Benjamin M., 1926 (Box 14)
  - Geneticist-Demographer Training Program, 1965-1966; 17.0 Item(s) (Box 14)
    Fellowships, assistantships; Population genetics; Population, demography; Research support; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
  - Gerould, John H. (Box 14)
  - Gillette, Clarence Preson (Box 14)
  - Gillette, J. M. (Box 14)
  - Gilmore, Ralph L. (Box 14)
  - Godwin, W. F., 1926 (Box 14)
  - Gottesman, Irving I. (Box 14)
  - Graham, Thomas E. (Box 15)
  - Grant, J. C. Boileau (Box 15)
  - Grant, J. R. (Box 15)
  - Grant, Madison (Box 15)
  - Green, Charles R. (Box 15)
  - Greene, Ransom A. (Box 15)
  - Greenfield High School (Box 15)
  - Grier, Norman Mac D. (Box 15)
  - Griffin, L. E. (Box 15)
  - Griffin, William E., 1926 (Box 15)
  - Grimwood, E. A. (Box 15)
  - Grobe, Ida (Box 15)
    2nd International Congress of Eugenics, Executive Committee
  - Gross, Alfred O. (Box 15)
  - Groves, Ernest R. (Box 15)
  - Guyer, M. F. (Box 15)
  - Habenicht, Mae (Box 15)
  - Haines, Thomas H. (Box 15)
  - Hale, Harrison (Box 15)
  - Hall, Arnold B. (Box 15)
  - Hall, Fred. L. (Box 15)
  - Hall, Robert A. (Box 15)
  - Hamilton Bank Note Engraving and Printing Company (Box 15)
  - Hamlett, G. W. D. (Box 15)
  - Hankins, Frank H. (Box 15)
  - Hansell, Marion (Box 15)
  - Hansen, J. A., 1926 (Box 15)
  - Hanson, Frank Blair (Box 15)
  - Harlow, Hiram, II (Box 15)
  - Harper, Roland M. (Box 15)
  - Harris, Sidney E., 1926 (Box 15)
  - Harvard Growth Study, 3rd, 1966-1970; 3 folders (59 items) (Box 15)
    Behavioral genetics, IQ; Embryology, developmental genetics; Harvard University; Research support; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs -- Population Council
  - Hayes, W. H. (Box 15)
  - Heard, Maie Bartlett (Box 15)
  - Hester, H. H., 1926 (Box 15)
  - Hester, St. Clair, 1926 (Box 15)
    Church of the Messiah sermon on eugenics.
  - Higgins, Frances (Box 15)
  - Hill, Ruth K., 1926 (Box 15)
  - Himes, Norman E. (Box 15)
  - Hines, Herbert Waldo (Box 15)
  - Hodder, Jessie D. (Box 15)
  - Hodges, Louis S. (Box 15)
  - Hodskins, Morgan B. (Box 15)
  - Hogsett, James L. (Box 15)
  - Holmes, C. O. (Box 15)
  - Holt, Lt. Emmett (Box 15)
  - Hopkins Fund (Box 15)
  - Horsfall, Frank (Box 15)
  - Horsley, J. Shelton (Box 15)
  - Horst, E. Clemens (Box 15)
  - Householder, E. F. (Box 15)
  - How to Prepare a Family Pedigree (Box 15)
  - Howell, W. H. (Box 15)
  - Huddleston, George (Box 15)
  - Huestis, R. R. (Box 15)
  - Hughey, R. M. (Box 15)
  - Human Betterment Association of America (Box 15)
  - Hunt, Caroline L. (Box 15)
  - Hunt, Harrison R. (Box 15)
  - Hunting, Nathan J. (Box 15)
  - Huntington, Ellsworth, 1928, 1971 (Box 15)
    Includes biographical sketch and statement of Huntington's relationship to eugenics and the AES.
  - Huntington, Henry S., 1928; 6 folders (Box 15)
    Includes sermons on eugenics, "A debt to our descendents " and "An elect race" (folder 2); "The more abundant life" and "Eugenics and the church" (folder 3); "Eugenics and the Church" and "Eugenics" (folder 4); "Eugenics and the church" (two versions, folder 5); "Eugenics and the Church" (three versions, folder 6).
    Short, Dallas L.
    Soper, Edmund D.
  - Huntting, H. R. (Box 15)
  - Hurie, Wylie L. (Box 15)
  - Hutchins, C. L. (Box 15)
  - Ingraham, Clarence B. (Box 16)
  - International Commission on Eugenics (Box 16)
    Ad Interim Committe of the USA - Minutes
  - International Congress of Eugenics, 2nd. Executive Committee -- Minutes, 1921-1924; 4.0 Item(s) (Box 16)
    Committee activities; Conferences and symposia; Eugenics; International Congress of Eugenics -- Second Congress
  - Ives, Hilda L. (Box 16)
  - Jennings, Herbert Spencer (Box 16)
  - Jensen, Howard E. (Box 16)
  - Johnson, Roswell H., 1927-1940; 23.0 Item(s) (Box 16)
    American Eugenics Society; Biographical and personal data; Committee activities -- Pennsylvania; Committee activities -- Utah
  - Jones, Harold E. (Box 16)
  - Jones, Lawrence M. (Box 16)
  - Jordan, H. E. (Box 16)
  - Judge, Charles T. (Box 16)
  - Kamin, Leon J. (Box 16)
  - Kay, W. J. (Box 16)
  - Kaye, V. C. (Box 16)
  - Keast, Lewis, 1926 (Box 16)
  - Kellogg, Vernon (Box 16)
  - Kern, Mrs. John W. (Box 16)
  - King, William F. (Box 16)
  - Kinmouth, Raymond A. (Box 16)
  - Kirby, George H. (Box 16)
  - Kirkpatrick, Edwin A., 1927-1931; 31.0 Item(s) (Box 16)
    American Eugenics Society; Committee activities -- Massachusetts; Political issues
  - Kirkwood, Irwin, in re (Box 16)
  - Kiser, Clyde V. -- Types of Demographic Data... (Box 16)
  - Knox, Sarah T. (Box 16)
  - Koch, Edw W. (Box 16)
  - Ladas, Constantine P. (Box 16)
  - Lalor Foundtion (Box 16)
  - Landsdowne, Burdette (Box 16)
  - Lane, Alfred C. (Box 16)
  - Lane, H. H. (Box 16)
  - Lang, Walter E. (Box 16)
  - Lauer, E. H. (Box 16)
  - Laughlin, H. H. (Box 16)
    2nd International Congress of Eugenics. Exec. Committee
  - Laughton, George (Box 16)
  - Levin, Louis H. (Box 16)
  - Lewis, E. (Box 16)
  - Lewis, J. F. (Box 16)
  - Lewonton, R. C. (Box 16)
  - Lieber, Emma (Box 16)
  - Lindbergh, Charles, 1952-1972; 25.0 Item(s) (Box 16)
    American Eugenics Society; Conferences and symposia; Congratulations, greetings, thanks; Eugenics; Human genetics; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
  - Little, Clarence Cook (Box 16)
  - Loeb, Leo (Box 16)
  - Long, Mrs. C. R. (Box 16)
  - Lorenz, William F. (Box 16)
  - Lorimer, Frank (Box 16)
  - Lowrey, P. O., 1926 (Box 16)
  - Lucas, F. A. (Box 16)
  - McAfee, John A. (Box 16)
  - MacArthur, Kenneth C., 1926-1928 (Box 16)
    Federated Church sermons on eugenics (Second prize in 1926).
  - McCarthy, Gerald M. (Box 16)
  - MacCorison, Carl C. (Box 16)
  - MacCullum, John Archibald, 1926 (Box 16)
  - MacCurdy, H. M. (Box 16)
  - MacDougall, Mary Stuart (Box 16)
  - McGonagle, C. A. (Box 16)
  - Macklin, C. C. (Box 16)
    Thompson, W. P.
    Grant, J. C. Boileau
    Fraser, C. McLean
    Shaner, Ralph F.
  - McPherson, George E. (Box 16)
  - Majestic Hardware and Picture Frame Company (Box 16)
  - Marley, H. P., 1927 (Box 16)
  - Marshall, H. L. (Box 16)
  - Martin, Alleyne (Box 16)
  - Martin, J. Holmes (Box 16)
  - Marvin, Cloyd Heck (Box 16)
  - Massachusetts Agricultural College (Box 16)
  - Mayer, Harry H., 1926 (Box 16)
  - Mead, J. Calvin, 1926 (Box 16)
  - Meyer, Adolf (Box 16)
  - Middleton, Austin R. (Box 16)
  - Milbank Memorial Fund, 1959-1972; 99.0 Item(s) (Box 16)
    American Eugenics Society; Conferences and symposia; Research support; Solicitations for support or contribution
    - Milbank Memorial Fund (Box 16)
    - Milbank Memorial Fund Grants, 1959...; 4 folders (Box 16)
  - Miles, A. F. (Box 16)
  - Milligan, James W. (Box 16)
  - Morgan, Roy (Box 16)
  - Morrow, Clarence A. (Box 16)
  - Morton, David (Box 16)
  - Mosher, Mrs. E. A. (Box 17)
  - Mossman, George A. (Box 17)
  - Mudd, Stuart (Box 17)
  - Muller, Herman J. (Box 17)
  - Mumford, Eben (Box 17)
  - Mumford, Mrs. Eben (Box 17)
  - Murphy, Albert J. (Box 17)
  - Murphy, Helen E. (Box 17)
  - Nabours, Robert K. (Box 17)
  - National Health Council (Box 17)
  - New Haven Arena Company (Box 17)
  - New Salem High School (Box 17)
  - New York State College of Agriculture (Box 17)
  - New York State Department of Agriculture and Markets (Box 17)
  - New York State Department of Labor (Box 17)
  - Newman, H. H. (Box 17)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 17)
  - Northampton Fair (Box 17)
  - O'Brien, J. J. and Son (Box 17)
  - Olmstead, Allen S. (Box 17)
  - Olson, Harry (Box 17)
  - Osborn, Frederick (Box 17-18)
    - American Foundations and Population Problems (Box 17)
    - History of the American Eugenics Society, 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Frederick Osborn Papers, 1928-1971; 27 folders (178 items) (Box 17)
      American Eugenics Society; Behavioral genetics, IQ; Carnegie Corporation; Eugenics; History of biology, especially genetics; Human evolution, physical anthropology; Human genetics; National Research Council; Political issues -- Birth control; Population genetics; Population, demography; Publication; Research support; Reviews; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs -- Population Council; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.; World War II -- Impact on science
      - Organization of National Research Council (Natural Sciences - Research Council), December 4, 1928; 5p. (Box 17, Folder 1)
        "Memorandum for Eugenics file."
      - Memo re: Preliminary study by Carnegie Inst. of W[ashington] on status of human measuurement as related to eugenical research, September 3, 1929; 5p. (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Characteristics and Differential Fertility of American Population Groups, May 10, 1933; 15p. (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Memorandum on the Eugenics Situation in the United States, May 24, 1933; 7p. (Box 17, Folder 2)
        "Written for Rockefeller interests. Not used."
      - Most Brains in the West and Cities-The Literary Digest, June 3, 1933; 1p. (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Preliminary Announcement -- Social Eugenics, 1933; 1p. (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - A Eugenics Program for the United States, before December 1935; 3 copies of pam. (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Social Morality in a Diminishing Population, November 14, 1934; 16p. (Box 17, Folder 3)
        Includes printed version of article.
      - Notes for Eugenic Program, November 14, 1934; 3p. (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - Heredity and Environment, March 13, 1934; 11p. (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - Development of Eugenic Policies, February 15, 1935; 12p. (Box 17, Folder 4)
        Galley proof.
      - Birth Control and Birth Promotion, March 12, 1935; 3p. (Box 17, Folder 5)
        Also mss. notes for article and printed version in Birth Control Review 2 (April 1935): 4.
      - Draft and Comments Re Eugenics Program, April 10, 1935; 10p. (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Lorimer, Frank -- ALS to Frederick Osborn, April 12, 1935; 2p. (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Eugenics Program for the United States, June 13, 1935; 2p. (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Significance of Differential Reproduction, May 3, 1935; 3p. (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Significance of Differential Reproduction for American Educational Policy, October, 1935; 9p. (Box 17, Folder 5)
        Version as printed in Social Forces 14 (1935): 23-32. Also newspaper clipping
      - Excerpts from letters regarding "A Eugenics Program for the United States", October, 1935; 5p. (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Memorandum on the Significance of the Different Rates at Which Various Population Groups in the United States are Reproducing, December 7, 1935; 1p. (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Memo Re: Foundation Policy, April 13, 1936; 4p. (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Moral Responsibilities of Parenthood, May 20, 1936; 4p. (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Basis of Eugenic Selection, June 6, 1936; 9p. (Box 17, Folder 6)
        Includes pritned version of article in Eugenical News 21 (1936): 69-73.
      - Measures of Quality in the Study of Population, 1936; 21p. (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Major Aspects of Eugenic Selection, August 24, 1936; 15p. (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - Application of Measures of Quality, [1936]; 10p. (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - Studies in Human Behavior - Book review for Journal of Heredity, February 23, 1937; 3p. (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Summary of Proceedings-Conference on Eugenics in Relation to Nursing, February 24, 1937; 3p. (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Memorandum of Remarks at Birth Control Meeting at Mrs. Roland Redmond's house, March 1, 1937; 3p. (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Culture-Complex of Family Limitation-Its Social and Medical Significance, April 21, 1937; 5p. (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - "Raw Materials, Population Pressure and War"-book review, April 28, 1937; 3p. (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Report of Round Table on Population Studies-Milbank Memorial Fund Conference., April 29-30, 1937; 9p. (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Remarks at Round Table of "Experts" discussion of eugenic policies [Annual Meeting, American Eugenics Society], May 11, 1937; 3p. (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Introductory Remarks by Frederick Osborn at Annual Meeting, American Eugenics Society, May 14, 1937; 2p. (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Implications of the New Studies in Population and Psychology for the Development of Eugenic Philosophy, June 1, 1937; 6p. (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Eugenics-An Elementary Text, August 25, 1937; 3p. (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Major Aspects of Eugenic Selection, February 1937; 14p. (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Philosophy of Eugenics, January 30, 1938; 2p. (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - American Eugenics Society-Annual Meeting 1938-Remarks, May 5, 1938; 6p. (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Science Contributes-Social Implications of the Eugenic Program-Child Study, January 1939; 3p. (Box 17, Folder 9)
        Published version from Child Study
      - Quality of the American Population-Journal of Contraception, February 1939; 3p. (Box 17, Folder 9)
        Published version from Journal of Contraception
      - Significance to Medicine of Present Population Trends, April 6, 1939; 20p. (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Dedicatory Exercises of the American Museum of Health-Hall of Man, New York World's Fair, June 17, 1939; 1p. (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - Comprehensive Program of Eugenics and its Social Implications, Spring-Summer 1939; 6p. (Box 17, Folder 10)
        Published version from Living.
      - To What Extent is a Science of Man Possible?, November 1939; 8p. (Box 17, Folder 10)
        Published version from Scientific Monthly 49 (1939): 452-459.
      - Statement on Eugenics and the Family, National Conference on Family Relations, January 16, 1940; 7p. (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - Eugenic Significance of Planned Parenthood in a Democracy-Birth Control Federation, January 23, 1940; 7p. (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - Eugenics of Human Reproduction-Human Fertility, February 1940; 4p. (Box 17, Folder 10)
        Published version from Human Fertility 5 (1940): 1-4.
      - Implications of the 39th Yearbook for Eugenics-National Society for the Study of Education, February 26, 1940; 7p. (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - Population Trends and Public Health Problems-Conference of Health Officers and Public Health Nurses, Saratoga Springs, June 26, 1940; 11p. (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - Memorandum on Corporation Grants in the Field of Human Biology, August 1940; 8p. (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - Improving the Quality of the Next Generation, October 16, 1940; 12p. (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - Adventures in Science, CBS Radio Program, 1940, November 14, 1940; 4p., 2 copies (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - Radio Program-New Jersey College of Agriculture Homemakers Forum Program, December 18, 1940; 8p. (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - Excerpts from talk, "Human Ability-Democracy's Basic Defense"-Army and Navy Committee on Welfare and Recreation, March 31, 1941; 2p. (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - Eugenics and National Defense, March 31, 1940; 4p. (Box 17, Folder 11)
        Also includes published version from Journal of Heredity 32 (1941): 203-204.
      - Heredity and Practical Genetics Today - Is Eugenics Practical?, March 2, 1948; 14p. (Box 17, Folder 12)
        Includes two printed copies from Eugenical News 33 (1948): 1-6
      - Preparing for Parenthood, [1948?]; 13p. (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - The Eugenic Hypothesis: Part I: Positive Eugenics, June 1951; 5p. (Box 17, Folder 13)
        Also includes published version from Eugenical News 36, 2 (1951): 19-21.
      - The Eugenic Hypothesis: Part II: Negative Eugenics, March 1952; 7p. (Box 17, Folder 13)
        Also includes published version from Eugenical News 37, 1 (1952): 6-9.
      - Selective Processes in the Differential Fertility on Genetics Endowment, July-August 1952; 8p. (Box 17, Folder 13)
        Printed version from American Naturalist 86 (1952): 203-211.
      - Possible Effects of Differential Fertility on Genetic Endowment, September 1952; 7p., 2 copies (Box 17, Folder 13)
        Printed version from Eugenical News 37, 3 (1952): 47-54.
      - New Trends in Human Evolution, November 12, 1952; 9p. (Box 17, Folder 14)
        Talk delivered at American Philosophical Society.
      - The Major Policies of the American Eugenics Society, May 12, 1940; 3p. (Box 17, Folder 14)
        Published version from Eugenical News 38, 2 (1953): 17-19
      - Freedom of Choice for Parenthood, June 1953; 6p. (Box 17, Folder 14)
        Published version from Eugenical News 38, 2 (1953): 25-31.
      - Contribution of Planned Parenthood to the Future of America, September 1953; 5p. (Box 17, Folder 14)
        Published version from Eugenical News Quarterly (1953): 79-84
      - Some New Horizons for Medicine and Public Health, February 11, 1954; 15p., partial second copy (Box 17, Folder 15)
      - Effect of Birth Control on the Intelligence and Character of Succeeding Generations, June 1954; 4p. (Box 17, Folder 15)
        Published version from Eugenics Quarterly 1 (1954): 27-31
      - Eugenics Credo, July 27, 1954; 4p., and drafts (Box 17, Folder 15)
      - Correspondence Relating to Eugenics Credo, August 1954; 4 items (Box 17, Folder 15)
      - Relation of Population Changes to the Distribution of Genetic Factors-World Population Conference, October 27, 1954; 15p. (Box 17, Folder 16)
      - F.O.'s Comments on Neel and Shull's Chapter on Eugenics (Chapter 20), November 1954; 4p., plus copies and drafts (Box 17, Folder 16)